

### Hossein Abedi

Isfahan, Iran

Senior Full Stack Developer

Tel: +98-913-3701711 h.abedi@yahoo.com Skype ID: abedi.skype

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hosseinabedi

### **SUMMARY**

Self-motivated senior full stack developer with a passion for quality, innovation and building world-class applications with the aim of improving people's life quality. Having 8+ years of experience and working in multiple startups, I am always really eager to learn, and completely ready to develop innovative and creative solution for real-world problems. In addition, being a helpful member of a professional team with an interesting goal and a good culture that improves everyone is the best thing I really enjoy.

### **HIGHLIGHTS**

Skills	Experience
Node.js / Express, TypeScript	A long background experience in ASP.NET / MVC / C# / MSSQL
MongoDB, Neo4j	Good at designing algorithms and really enjoy it
JavaScript, ES6	Worked as the head of software development teams
Linux CentOS, Ubuntu	Worked with remote software development teams as project coordinator(based in Tehran, Iran and India)
JQuery, HTML5, Pug/Jade, CSS3	Good background in Artificial Intelligence
Spring boot, Java	Designing crawlers, working with financial time-series and many other interesting and practical tools.
Git	Experience of startup failure (Not mine)!

### **EXPERIENCE**

Senior Fullstack Developer Eghtesadium.ir Oct. 2020 - persent	Persian Economy News Aggregator. It constantly crawls 30+ Persian economy news websites and after adding appropriate tags, publishes the news in relevant categories.  NodeJS / Express / MongoDB / Redis / Socket.IO / CSS / HTML
Senior Backend Developer RESUMI Isatiss Co. May. 2018 – Oct. 2020	Developed a business social networking app for professional people and businesses. I have developed the backend and the website(The website is still under development).  Available online: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ir.isatiss.resumi  Backend: Java, Spring boot, Neo4j Web: Nodejs, TypeScript, Redis, VueJs
Web Developer Hostell.ir 2017	A listing website for web-hosting plans that helps people to find their most fit web-hosting plan and saves them time. The web-hosting plans are added by businesses to the website.  NodeJS / Express / MongoDB and deployed in Linux CentOS, clustered with PM2

#### Web Developer

Keliyak.com Monam24.ir Rondbook.com

2016

Developer and R&D member Parto-Ara Co.

Isfahan, Iran Jan 2017 – Jan 2018 Rondbook is a domain marketplace, Keliyak is a B2B Directory, And Monam24 is a center that republishes current tenders under offer in Iran.

ASP.NET MVC5, C#, EntityFraework Code First, SQL Server, JQuery, JavaScript, CSS, HTML and AJAX

Developing and maintaining of a monitoring, repair and maintenance management system for Mobarakeh Steel Complex, Isfahan, Iran. We installed it in the electric arc furnace (EAF) unit to balance the workload of the workers, equipments and heavy vehicles and increase the throughput of the unit. We were 10 people working on this project with different roles including managers, networking specialist and developers (3 developers).

WPF, C#, WCF, SQL Server and EntityFraework Code First

# Team head and Senior Developer

Salmanian Co.

Isfahan, Iran Aug. 2013-Sep. 2016 1) A ground station control software. We were a team of 5 developers which were working together based on scrum.

WPF/C#, Prism, SQL Server, Entity Framework

2) A software for designing Propellers especially for ships and underwater vehicles such as AUV and ROV. We were 2 developers and a marine engineer on this project.

WPF, C#, C++ and a library for 3D surface and solid Modeling called OpenCASCADE

3) A GPS-free algorithm for determining the robot position. I implemented the algorithm on a real ground robot to show the effectiveness of the algorithm. We also used an augmented reality library to determine the 3D position of the robot using some 2D patterns.

C++, C# and WPF, used Kalman-filter

# .NET Developer Graph Co.

Isfahan, Iran 2008-2010 Developed a software called Hezareh to manage the entire process of printing and publishing everything from a book to a business card. Two versions were released. The project were developed using Visual C# and SQL Server. It was able to update itself from the Internet.

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

### Robotic Developer IUT Artificial Intelligence and Robotics Lab.

IUT, Isfahan, Iran 2011-2012 Developed a controller for an ROV (remotely operated underwater vehicle) in C. The controller (underwater unit) had to communicate with the surface unit (which was developed in Visual C#). It had to send sensors data to the surface unit and receive operator commands to apply them to the ROV actuators. I also developed some parts of the surface unit and added some interactive 3D graphical parts in WPF to it. C, C#, WPF

### **EDUCATION**

MSc - Artificial Intelligence Isfahan University of Technology, Isfahan, Iran 2011-2013

Thesis: A scale-invariant descriptor based on covariance matrix for 3D point cloud matching

BSc - Software Engineering Azad University Isfahan, Iran 2005-2010

Thesis: A time-table scheduling software based on Genetic Algorithm

## Skills

Node and Essentials	L*	Other	L	Worked/Familiar with	L	have used	L
Node.js / Express	Α	ASP.NET MVC	Α	Scrum	В	OpenCV	Α
MongoDB	Α	C#	Α	Unit testing	В	Point Clouds Library(PCL)	Α
JavaScript, ES6	Α	C/C++	Α	Android	В	CGAL(Computational Geometry Algorithms Library)	В
MVC	Α	Spring-boot	Α	DirectAdmin	В	OpenCASCADE(3D surface and solid modeling)	В
JQuery	Α	Java	Α	CPanel	В	DotNetNuke	В
Sails.js	Α	WPF	Α	Plesk	В	NopCommerce	Α
Pug,HTM5,CSS3	Α	MATLAB	Α	NetBeans	В		
Twitter Bootstrap	Α	R	В	bitcoind	В		
Semantic-UI	Α	Python	В	FreeDOS	В		
Node and Essentials	L	Other	L	Worked/Familiar with	L	have used	L
MS Visual Studio Code	Α	TypeScript	Α	Code::Blocks	Α		
React & React Native	B⁺	MQL5	Α	TurboC++	Α		
SQL	В	Assembly	Α	Asana(asana.com as on	line p	project management software)	Α
Git	В	MS Visual Studio	Α	CorelDRAW			
Linux CentOS	В	MS SQL Server	Α	Trello			
Apache	В	PostgreSQL	Α	Slack			
Redis	В	Apache Cassandra	В				

<sup>\*</sup>L: Level of proficiency (A: Proficient, B: Not Proficient but Familiar/Worked with nearly good)